ALONZO KING III

FULL STACK DEVELOPER

🔁 aking893.ak@gmail.com 📞 614-972-0761 in Alonzo King iii 🗘 KingBoolean89

SUMMARY

Full-stack developer with a industrial, logistical and project management background, with exposure to Lean Six sigma. Possess nearly 2 years of front-end development. Along with experience using E-commerce and website platforms such as Wix, Shopify and Weebly. I've recently received a Software Development Certification at We Can Code IT, a full-stack Java bootcamp in Columbus, Ohio. The program gives you a solid foundation in software development best practices, teaches a server-side language(Java) and gives you the skills needed to thrive and work expeditiously in a Scrum and/or Agile environment. Along with the skills to utilize cultural differences in order to enhance the users experience.

EMPLOYMENT

We Can Code It · Software development Apprentice · Sept. 2018 to Dec. 2018

Freelance · Freelance Web Developer · Mar. 2017 to Current · Columbus, Ohio

>Build responsive websites and/or applications utilizing HTML, CSS and Javascript.

>Build dynamic web applications utilizing the Spring Framework for backend and React.js for the frontend of the application.

Vista Logistics · Receiving/Inventory control specialist · July 2017 to Oct. 2017 · Columbus, Ohio

Responsible for receiving and tracking inbound and outbound products. Utilize a variety of warehouse management and inventory systems, to streamline logistical processes and create visibility within the companies supplychain. Along with the operation and maintenance of a variety of industrial lifts.

Yenkin Majestic · Chemical reactor operator · July 2016 to June 2017 · Columbus, Ohio

Followed standard procedures to make resin and basic plastics. Engaged in small projects to correct standard procedures for operating processes and error/defect prevention. Along with minor maintenance duties, daily reports, lab testing, recording results and analyzing graphical data.

EDUCATION

Sept. 2018 to Dec. 2018 We Can Code IT Java Certification

Sept. 2016 to Current Columbus State Community College AAS, Supply Chain Management

PROJECTS

Oct. 2018 Language Barrier

Tech used: Java, SpringFramework,H2 database,Git,ThymeLeaf,HTML5,CSS3,Javascript,GitHub,JPA,TDD,

Description: Created a customized API to make a simple full-stack application

Nov. 2018 React-Weather-App

Tech used: React, GitHub, Git, Javascript,

Description: A simple application that displays the weather of the location the user enters, utilizing an external API

Oct. 2018 Spirits and Stogies

Description: Full-stack cigar and alcohol pairing blog site

July 2018 Gbmcartoon website

 $Tech\ used:\ HTML5, CSS3, Bootstrap, Git, Git Hub, Javascript,$

Description: Landing page built for a client to increase streams and simple integration with the clients social network.

June 2017 SheDeserve.com

Tech used:Shopify,

Description:E-commerce website built to raise funds for a personal cause

Nov. 2018 to Dec. 2018 CSP Dash(Prototype)

Tech used: Spring Framework, Java, HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, H2 Database, JPA, REST, React, Chart. js, Papa Parse, TDD,

 $Description: Full-stack \ application \ built to \ streamline \ financial \ processes for \ Fedex \ Contractors. \ It \ parses \ data \ from \ a \ CSV \ file \ , \ checks \ for \$

possible errors, displays data using tables along with graphical representation.

ACTIVITIES

Jan. 2019 to Current Gingerbreadman cartoon link page · Web developer

HTML5,CSS3,Javascript,Bootstrap

Jan. 2019 to Current Northland Church of Christ website · Web Developer

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, Bootstrap

Jan. 2019 to Current Northland Church of Christ Attendance App · Web Developer

HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, React, React strap, Mongo DB, Express, Node. js,

Dec. 2018 to Current CSP Dash(Production build) · Application Developer

Description: Full-stack application built to streamline financial processes for Fedex Contractors. It parses data from a CSV file, checks for

possible errors, displays data using tables along with graphical representation.

https://resume.creddle.io/